Guide to the Jeannette M. Hitchcock Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Jeannette M. Hitchcock papers
1932-1974
SC0148
Hitchcock, Jeannette M. (Jeannette McCrory).
Hitchcock, Jeannette M., (Jeannette McCrory)
Hopkins, Jeannette Hitchcock, 1890-1976.
1 Linear feet
Primarily correspondence, articles, speeches and unpublished papers concerned with both library and nonlibrary topics. Correspondents include Arundell Esdaile, Sir Frank Francis and Patricia Eccles.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Jeannette Hitchcock Hopkins Estate, 1976, and Mrs. Patricia Eccles, 1977.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
A graduate of Stanford (1914), Jeannette Hitchcock came to the Stanford Library in 1923, was appointed Keeper of Rare Books in the University Libraries (1936-1947) and was later Chief of the Division of Special Collections (1947-1955). She was married to Franklin L. Hopkins.
Description of the Collection
Primarily correspondence, articles, speeches and unpublished papers concerned with both library and nonlibrary topics. Correspondents include Arundell Esdaile, Sir Frank Francis and Patricia Eccles.
Access Terms
Eccles, Patricia.; Eccles, Patricia.; Esdaile, Arundell.; Esdaile, Arundell.; Francis, Frank Chalton,, Sir,, 1901-1988.; Francis, Frank, Sir.; Hitchcock, Jeannette M. (Jeannette McCrory).; Hopkins, Jeannette Hitchcock, 1890-1976.; Stanford University -- General subdivision--Employees.;; Stanford University. Libraries. Department of Special Collections and University Archives.
Collection Contents
- Correspondence
  - Correspondence between Jeannette Hopkins and Stanford Library chiefs about her gifts to the Bender Room. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Correspondents: Julius Barrclay, Chief of Special Collections; Elmer Grieder, Associate Director of Stanford Libraries; Ray Swank, Director of Stanford Libraries.
  - Correspondence received from Arundell Esclaile., 1934-1956 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence received from Sir Frank Francis, Director of the British Museum, mainly acknowledging her gifts of Bender Room Keepsakes to the Museum. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous World War II, Correspondence received from Europe, 1937-1948 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Correspondent.s: Lt. William Clarkson; John D. Couley; Mms. Isaac-Chareau; H.H. Lloyd; Beatrice White.
  - Miscellaneous domestic correspondence., 1945-1968 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "An English Chroicle: Bound copies of J.H.H.'s letters written from London, September 1937-February 1938 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous clippings, photographs, cards, and articles which had been inserted between pages of "An English Chronicle." (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Articles, Speeches, and Unpublished Papers
  - Papers about. Stanford Libraries, especially Special Collections (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Articles, speeches, and papers relevant to her participation in library associations: American Library Association, California Library Association, Bay District Library Discussion Group Committee. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Articles, speeches, and papers on miscellaneous, non-library topics (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Biographical Material
  - Graduation diploma, Stanford, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Stanford University Faculty records (personnel forms) completed by J.H.H., and letters of recommendation pertaining to them. (Box 1, Folder 12)